hello friends and
welcome you are with deepak mani and we
are in this two minutes money
and personal finance show yesterday's
episode we discussed
about travel insurance after viewing
that
if you are connected and asked
tell me what overseas
health insurance is and how
is it different from the overseas
travel policy and which one is better
clearly as the name suggests overseas
health insurance will take care of
any health emergencies when you are
traveling
abroad so if there is an accident
if you get hospitalized if you need to
be
treated on an emergency basis
this overseas mediclaim or health
insurance policy
will cover those expenses
these are specifically
for overseas travel only
they will not cover you for any
hospitalization or health expenses
from the country of origin where you are
traveling so if i buy the policy from
india
if you get hospitalized in india you
don't get anything that's the way it
works
the other one the travel policy now the
travel policy as we saw yesterday
covers you for trip delays
flight cancellations loss of baggage
loss of passports and other documents
plus
it also covers you for health
emergencies like
accidents hospitalizations and
treatments
the price difference between both these
policies is very very small
so if i were you and if i was traveling
abroad instead of buying the stand-alone
health insurance policy i would buy the
travel insurance policy which in
addition to covering
what this health insurance policies
cover
they also cover your trip delays
flight cancellations loss of baggage
passports
and other things so the basic difference
standalone health health plus travel
plus documentation plus
trip delays and if i have to choose
i have to choose the travel insurance
policy
compared to the overseas health
insurance policy
we will talk more about this and other
things in the next episode stay tuned